<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Luke Stahl&apos;s Blog</title><description>Articles on web development, CMS platforms, AI tools, and developer marketing</description><link>https://lucasstahl.com/</link><language>en-us</language><item><title>Can a modern website run on Markdown alone?</title><link>https://lucasstahl.com/blog/markdown-vs-cms/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lucasstahl.com/blog/markdown-vs-cms/</guid><description>A clear look at how far Markdown and AI can go, where a CMS becomes necessary, and why visual development offers a different approach entirely.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/markdown-vs-cms/Markdown_hero_1200_png.png&quot; alt=&quot;Markdown_hero_1200.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A debate surfaced over the weekend about whether teams still need a CMS at all. The idea is simple. If AI can draft content, migrate files, clean up structure, and commit everything to your repo, maybe you don’t need a content system. Everything becomes Markdown. Everything lives in Git. AI handles the busywork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a compelling argument for code-first teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the real question is bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can an entire production website be built and maintained this way, or are there parts of a CMS that AI and Markdown still can’t replace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And once you widen the scope to the whole website, a third option starts to matter too: visual development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how these models actually compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The argument for Markdown and AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leerob.com/agents&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; has always been appealing to developers. It’s simple, local, versioned, and transparent. With AI acting on files the same way developers already do, a lot of friction disappears. You can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;draft content in your editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use agents to clean up structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generate frontmatter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reorganize folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;handle bulk changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;commit and deploy without leaving your flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a fully technical team, this model feels clean. There are no CMS dashboards to maintain, no API layers to wire up, and no separate content environments to manage. Everything lives in one place, and automation handles the repetitive work. It’s a real advantage for teams that operate entirely in code. But it also assumes something important: every contributor works like a developer. And most websites aren’t run that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where Markdown starts to fall short&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown works well when content is simple and the team is small. That’s why some engineering-led teams can run it without friction. But once a website becomes a system instead of a collection of documents, Markdown introduces gaps that aren’t obvious until you hit them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some websites genuinely don’t need structured content, workflows, localization, or a cross-functional editing model. If your site is simple and your team is entirely technical, Markdown can work fine. But if your website relies on these capabilities, getting them in a Markdown workflow means building and maintaining them yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/markdown-vs-cms/Website_vs_Markdown_png.png&quot; alt=&quot;Website_vs_Markdown.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the big ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. No structured content model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some sites don’t need schema-level modeling. Many do. Production sites often rely on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reusable fragments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shared data across many surfaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown doesn’t enforce any of this. One missing field can break pages. One inconsistent value can break queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can bolt on schema validation, but at that point you’re recreating parts of a CMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. No safe editing environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown works for engineers. It doesn’t work for non-technical contributors. Even if AI generates the files, someone still ends up reviewing diffs or dealing with frontmatter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporting broader teams means building:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internal UIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guardrails around edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;validation layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, you&amp;#39;re asking non-technical contributors to operate in Git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. No preview tied to actual components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some engineering teams already maintain strong preview systems. Most don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without one, a Markdown file can’t show:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how a component renders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how content interacts with layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how changes ripple across a page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You only see the real outcome after a build or preview deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. No built-in workflows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Websites need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;approvals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;version history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scheduling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;role-based access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;localization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multi-surface consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown doesn’t support this. Reproducing it means building bots, branch rules, and CI automation to simulate editorial workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. No shared space for collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown keeps contributors split across tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developers in Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;designers in Figma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;marketers in docs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reviewers in comments elsewhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no shared environment for the website itself. Markdown is simple until the website isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can AI agents solve this gap?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI agents can automate a lot inside a Markdown workflow. They can generate files, rewrite content, reorganize structure, migrate documents, clean up frontmatter, and handle several repetitive tasks developers used to own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But agents don’t replace the systems that keep a full website consistent and safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To match what a CMS provides, AI agents would need to handle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;schema enforcement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;field validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relationship modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reference checks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;localization parity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;role-based permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;publishing controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;approvals and sequencing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;preview environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multi-surface consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can help with pieces of this, but it can’t &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get all of these capabilities in a Markdown world, you’d need to build:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your own schema engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your own validation pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your own preview pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your own workflow and approval model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your own contributor UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your own localization framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your own content governance rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your own automation to prevent destructive edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point, you’re not “avoiding a CMS.” You’ve built one. AI assists the work. It does not replace the infrastructure that coordinates it. This is the distinction most people miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The argument for a CMS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sanity.io/blog/you-should-never-build-a-cms&quot;&gt;CMS solves the problems Markdown can’t&lt;/a&gt;. It gives you structure, validation, workflows, and a safer way for non-technical contributors to manage content without touching code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t write inside the CMS. They publish inside the CMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the important distinction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if AI drafts and rewrites content, the CMS provides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a consistent schema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a place to enforce rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a predictable workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a safe environment to update live content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a shared model for content relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clear separation between editing and code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why CMSs exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not because writing is hard, but because maintaining content across teams requires structure that Markdown doesn’t provide on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But CMSs are not perfect either. They can feel disconnected from the real site. They often separate content from layout. Editors can break things. API layers add overhead. Preview systems vary in quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So even though a CMS solves real coordination problems, it introduces friction in other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why a third model matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The case for visual development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual development sits between Markdown and a CMS. It treats the website as a full system, not just content or code. It gives teams a shared environment with structure built in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a visual development model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developers define components, logic, and structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;designers work directly in the real layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;editors update content inside the same system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;schema and relationships stay consistent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;content and layout stay aligned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI operates with awareness of the actual components and fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It removes the separation between:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;content and layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;authors and developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code and preview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;structure and design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown doesn’t provide this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webflow.com/blog/headless-cms-developer-tradeoffs&quot;&gt;Headless CMSs&lt;/a&gt; rarely provide this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the role of AI changes completely in a visual development system. AI isn’t generating files in a vacuum. It works inside the actual structure of the site. That means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI site builders generate real pages using real components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI visual editing adjusts layout, spacing, and structure with context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI app scaffolding uses actual data models and extension points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI doesn’t sit on the side. It participates in the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual development builds the website as one environment instead of splitting it across tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the gap &lt;a href=&quot;https://webflow.com/&quot;&gt;Webflow&lt;/a&gt; fills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ℹ️ Some platforms even combine visual development with Git-based workflows, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.builder.io/fusion&quot;&gt;Builder.io&amp;#39;s Fusion&lt;/a&gt; approach, which shows there’s real demand for visual editing that still fits into an engineering-centric versioning model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So what does a team lose moving from a CMS to Markdown?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You lose:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;schema enforcement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relationship modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;predictable workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;safe editing environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shared context across teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reliable previews &lt;em&gt;(unless you maintain your own preview system)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;localization pipelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;role-based permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;structured publishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cross-page consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can rebuild some of this, but now you’re maintaining a custom system that grows in complexity as your website grows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What a team gains by going Markdown-first&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You gain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;full developer control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simpler architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fewer systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automation through agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;transparency through Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lower overhead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a strong option for small, fully technical teams with simple content needs and tight ownership over the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not designed for companies with cross-functional contributors or evolving structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What visual development offers instead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual development isn’t trying to be Markdown. It isn’t trying to be a CMS either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It offers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;structure like a CMS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flexibility like a codebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;real layout context like a design tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shared collaboration across roles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI that works inside the true structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developer extension points when needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the only model where the website stays a single source of truth for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/markdown-vs-cms/Webflow_AI_png.png&quot; alt=&quot;Webflow_AI.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers keep control. Designers keep fidelity. Marketers keep clarity. AI doesn’t act blindly. That’s why visual development matters in this debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The simple way to think about it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown + AI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great when the team is fully technical and the site structure is simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CMS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great when content structure, governance, and shared responsibility matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great when a website is treated as a unified system where design, content, development, and AI all work together with real context.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>CMS</category><category>Markdown</category><category>Visual Development</category></item><item><title>Inside my developer marketing stack</title><link>https://lucasstahl.com/blog/my-stack/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lucasstahl.com/blog/my-stack/</guid><description>Every builder finds their own rhythm. This is mine. A look at the tools I use every day in developer marketing, how they fit together, why they’ve stuck, and how they keep the work moving.</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/my-stack/My_Stack_png.png&quot; alt=&quot;My_Stack.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every builder has a rhythm to how they build. For me, that rhythm lives somewhere between code and content, the overlap where developer marketing happens. These tools help me stay organized, move faster, and keep projects on track without overcomplicating the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IDE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cursor.com/&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt; is now my main workspace after years in &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;. They share the same foundation and extensions, but Cursor feels like where things are moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Same integrations and ecosystem as VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiar setup that just works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI that’s advancing faster than VS Code, which is surprising since GitHub built Copilot first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I pair it with &lt;a href=&quot;https://claude.ai/code&quot;&gt;Claude Code&lt;/a&gt; in the terminal for context, explanations, and large-scale debugging when I need deeper insight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s less about what’s new and more about pace. Cursor feels like it’s evolving while VS Code feels like it’s coasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;AI chat tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/&quot;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; is my go-to for projects, building custom GPTs, and setting up connectors or integrations. I also use it for content curation when I’m gathering examples or early research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gemini.google.com/&quot;&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt; handles search and visual creation. Its new Nano Banana feature makes generating visual references surprisingly quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, both tools serve different purposes, but my guess is Gemini eventually edges out OpenAI. We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design and visual thinking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://figma.com/&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt; is where I build and prototype designs. I don’t use its AI features, they’re still behind the curve. What makes it useful is how quickly I can move from layout ideas to something ready for production. Components, variables, and shared libraries keep everything consistent without extra effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://excalidraw.com/&quot;&gt;Excalidraw&lt;/a&gt; is where I whiteboard. I sketch flows, map systems, and rough out diagrams before anything formal. A cheat code I use is generating Mermaid diagrams in ChatGPT to get a starting point, then rebuilding them in Excalidraw to make them clearer and more visual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analytics stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big part of developer marketing is understanding how people use what you build. These tools help turn product usage into insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://posthog.com/&quot;&gt;PostHog&lt;/a&gt; for web analytics, event tracking, and session replay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fullstory.com/&quot;&gt;FullStory&lt;/a&gt; for journey mapping and deeper behavioral insights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sigmacomputing.com/&quot;&gt;Sigma&lt;/a&gt; for the full view, from lead tracking to closed-won pipeline reporting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://looker.com/&quot;&gt;Looker&lt;/a&gt; for clean visualization and quick summaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn’t one analytics platform that does everything well. A mix is usually the reality, and this is the combination that works for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Marketing and SEO stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the set of tools I rely on to manage search, automation, and content performance. Each one plays a different role, from tracking technical SEO to finding new opportunities and testing campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ahrefs.com/&quot;&gt;Ahrefs&lt;/a&gt; is my go-to for monitoring technical SEO, tracking backlinks, and doing competitive keyword research or content gap analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://surferseo.com/&quot;&gt;SurferSEO&lt;/a&gt; helps grade keyword-focused content and tighten on-page structure before publishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ads.google.com/home/tools/keyword-planner/&quot;&gt;Google Keyword Planner&lt;/a&gt; is great for generating new ideas based on topics or URLs and gives solid monthly search volume data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ads.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Ads&lt;/a&gt; still earns its place, paid search still works, especially in developer marketing where people search everything (even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bing.com/&quot;&gt;Bing&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airops.com/&quot;&gt;AirOps&lt;/a&gt; is a newer tool I’ve been using for automation workflows, from competitive intel to content research, all built through AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://buffer.com/&quot;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt; is my social tool of choice, mainly because its free tier goes further than most and supports multiple platforms without friction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commonroom.io/&quot;&gt;Common Room&lt;/a&gt; helps track and understand community activity across social, forums, and other developer channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stack helps me connect research, creation, and distribution. It’s about staying close to what works and improving a little with each iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sales and enablement stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where product knowledge turns into enablement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gong.io/&quot;&gt;Gong&lt;/a&gt; for reviewing customer calls and spotting themes that shape positioning and messaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workramp.com/&quot;&gt;WorkRamp&lt;/a&gt; for internal education and onboarding content, keeping sales and marketing aligned on what’s new&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/slides/&quot;&gt;Figma Slides&lt;/a&gt; for building presentations with real design flexibility. It feels like designing, not fighting templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arcade.software/&quot;&gt;Arcade&lt;/a&gt; for creating interactive product demos that help explain features in context without heavy editing or production time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They keep information flowing and teams aligned on what actually matters, the customers using the product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collaboration stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaboration works best when it’s async, not noisy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notion.so/&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; is where I write everything, content drafts, specs, notes, and ideas. It’s underrated for collaboration and perfect for pulling in code snippets or assets. People think they need Google Docs, but they’re wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/&quot;&gt;Airtable&lt;/a&gt; is a dream for anyone who loves spreadsheets. It’s flexible, visual, and great for tracking content and projects. I’ve been a fan since day one, even if not everyone adopts it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; is the only real choice for team communication. I live and die by the save-for-later feature, and the new canvas tools are great for organizing thoughts. Don’t at me with Microsoft Teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loom.com/&quot;&gt;Loom&lt;/a&gt; is the best way to explain anything on video. It’s perfect for walkthroughs, feedback, or education. The editing tools are ok, not Descript-level, but work well enough. The AI still has some catching up to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stack makes it easy to share work, document ideas, and keep everyone aligned without the constant back-and-forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Developer and Data Stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where projects take shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for version control and collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://supabase.com/&quot;&gt;Supabase&lt;/a&gt; for quick databases and APIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vercel.com/&quot;&gt;Vercel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; for deployments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.warp.dev/&quot;&gt;Warp&lt;/a&gt; for a cleaner, more visual terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a reliable setup that scales smoothly and keeps development fast without adding unnecessary infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tools have stuck because they make the work smoother. They cover everything I need to build, write, and collaborate without slowing things down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stack will keep changing, but the goal won’t. &lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Teck Stack</category><category>AI</category><category>Developer Marketing</category></item></channel></rss>