<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Luke Stahl&apos;s Blog</title><description>Articles on web development, CMS platforms, AI tools, and developer marketing</description><link>https://lucasstahl.com/</link><language>en-us</language><item><title>Inside my developer marketing stack</title><link>https://lucasstahl.com/blog/my-stack/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lucasstahl.com/blog/my-stack/</guid><description>Every builder finds their own rhythm. This is mine. A look at the tools I use every day in developer marketing, how they fit together, why they’ve stuck, and how they keep the work moving.</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/my-stack/My_Stack_png.png&quot; alt=&quot;My_Stack.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every builder has a rhythm to how they build. For me, that rhythm lives somewhere between code and content, the overlap where developer marketing happens. These tools help me stay organized, move faster, and keep projects on track without overcomplicating the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IDE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cursor.com/&quot;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt; is now my main workspace after years in &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;. They share the same foundation and extensions, but Cursor feels like where things are moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Same integrations and ecosystem as VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiar setup that just works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI that’s advancing faster than VS Code, which is surprising since GitHub built Copilot first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I pair it with &lt;a href=&quot;https://claude.ai/code&quot;&gt;Claude Code&lt;/a&gt; in the terminal for context, explanations, and large-scale debugging when I need deeper insight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s less about what’s new and more about pace. Cursor feels like it’s evolving while VS Code feels like it’s coasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;AI chat tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.openai.com/&quot;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; is my go-to for projects, building custom GPTs, and setting up connectors or integrations. I also use it for content curation when I’m gathering examples or early research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gemini.google.com/&quot;&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt; handles search and visual creation. Its new Nano Banana feature makes generating visual references surprisingly quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, both tools serve different purposes, but my guess is Gemini eventually edges out OpenAI. We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design and visual thinking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://figma.com/&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt; is where I build and prototype designs. I don’t use its AI features, they’re still behind the curve. What makes it useful is how quickly I can move from layout ideas to something ready for production. Components, variables, and shared libraries keep everything consistent without extra effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://excalidraw.com/&quot;&gt;Excalidraw&lt;/a&gt; is where I whiteboard. I sketch flows, map systems, and rough out diagrams before anything formal. A cheat code I use is generating Mermaid diagrams in ChatGPT to get a starting point, then rebuilding them in Excalidraw to make them clearer and more visual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Analytics stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big part of developer marketing is understanding how people use what you build. These tools help turn product usage into insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://posthog.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PostHog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for web analytics, event tracking, and session replay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fullstory.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FullStory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for journey mapping and deeper behavioral insights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sigmacomputing.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sigma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the full view, from lead tracking to closed-won pipeline reporting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://looker.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for clean visualization and quick summaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn’t one analytics platform that does everything well. A mix is usually the reality, and this is the combination that works for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Marketing and SEO stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the set of tools I rely on to manage search, automation, and content performance. Each one plays a different role, from tracking technical SEO to finding new opportunities and testing campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ahrefs.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahrefs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is my go-to for monitoring technical SEO, tracking backlinks, and doing competitive keyword research or content gap analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://surferseo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SurferSEO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; helps grade keyword-focused content and tighten on-page structure before publishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ads.google.com/home/tools/keyword-planner/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Keyword Planner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is great for generating new ideas based on topics or URLs and gives solid monthly search volume data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ads.google.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Ads&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; still earns its place, paid search still works, especially in developer marketing where people search everything (even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bing.com/&quot;&gt;Bing&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airops.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirOps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a newer tool I’ve been using for automation workflows, from competitive intel to content research, all built through AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://buffer.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buffer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is my social tool of choice, mainly because its free tier goes further than most and supports multiple platforms without friction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commonroom.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Room&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; helps track and understand community activity across social, forums, and other developer channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stack helps me connect research, creation, and distribution. It’s about staying close to what works and improving a little with each iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sales and enablement stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where product knowledge turns into enablement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gong.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for reviewing customer calls and spotting themes that shape positioning and messaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workramp.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WorkRamp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for internal education and onboarding content, keeping sales and marketing aligned on what’s new&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/slides/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figma Slides&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for building presentations with real design flexibility. It feels like designing, not fighting templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arcade.software/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arcade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for creating interactive product demos that help explain features in context without heavy editing or production time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They keep information flowing and teams aligned on what actually matters, the customers using the product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collaboration stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaboration works best when it’s async, not noisy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notion.so/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is where I write everything, content drafts, specs, notes, and ideas. It’s underrated for collaboration and perfect for pulling in code snippets or assets. People think they need Google Docs, but they’re wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airtable.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airtable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a dream for anyone who loves spreadsheets. It’s flexible, visual, and great for tracking content and projects. I’ve been a fan since day one, even if not everyone adopts it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the only real choice for team communication. I live and die by the save-for-later feature, and the new canvas tools are great for organizing thoughts. Don’t at me with Microsoft Teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loom.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the best way to explain anything on video. It’s perfect for walkthroughs, feedback, or education. The editing tools are ok, not Descript-level, but work well enough. The AI still has some catching up to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stack makes it easy to share work, document ideas, and keep everyone aligned without the constant back-and-forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Developer and Data Stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where projects take shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for version control and collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://supabase.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supabase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for quick databases and APIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vercel.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vercel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for deployments thought I don’t have anything against &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; either. Not a super fan of Next.js so that does complicate things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.warp.dev/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for a cleaner, more visual terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a reliable setup that scales smoothly and keeps development fast without adding unnecessary infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tools have stuck because they make the work smoother. They cover everything I need to build, write, and collaborate without slowing things down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stack will keep changing, but the goal won’t. &lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Teck Stack</category></item></channel></rss>